you can buy them on
amazon.com you buy them on
Amazon was notter by amazoncom please
click my
affiliate give up your dream Jonathan
don't you're never gonna become an
Amazon affiliate
[Music]
[Applause]
all righty y'all time for another threat
locker lock down story okay picture this
you're on an internal pen test and you
finally got a foothold on a Target
machine you've reached the point where
it's time to Snoop around a little bit
and see if you can find these little
juicy pieces of information that allow
you to Pivot deeper into the network you
open up the desktop and what do you see
but what every hacker loves to see
passwords.com txt file you type cat or
type or whatever it is on Windows to get
the contents of that file and just as
you press enter the shell drops no why
did the shell
drop that my friend was a threat Locker
Canary file and that machine is now on
complete lockdown you're burnt and scene
I know I know I know that was traumatic
you all but I had to let you know what
kind of things threat Locker detect is
doing to hackers so if you or a love
hacker has experienced trauma at the
hands of threat Locker systems please
call call the threat Locker hacker
complaint number at 833 292
7732 all right guys let's go back to the
show alrighty Dr Bowman the time has
come thank you for coming back on the
Pod man thanks thanks for the
inite yeah I we we um I was thinking you
know oh I gotta have Bowman on and I
realized we actually did have you on in
an episode back in in the beginning of
the podcast episode 17 um with all those
all those hackers just kind of sitting
in a hotel room chatting about all the
bug stories so that was definitely a
great memory of mine that's a good
memory yeah it was just a some smallish
hotel room all on the bat because there
was no more space there and yeah I think
I described some book that help me to
create a music song and get it released
and all the hassle to get through to get
it actually there where I wanted it to
pop uh yeah but it was a good time and
I'm so honored that you guys still use
it in the podcast yeah dude we use it
every episode I think people really like
it at the end you know it's you know
because you go through the whole podcast
the intro music is really like all right
let's hype it up let's hype it up and
then at the end it's like okay now we're
just gonna mellow it out right at the
end right so to be one of the two like
Whitey cracker and me W yeah standing in
the credit next to whitey cracker come
on it just it just uh it adds to your
list of achievements man which is which
is where I wanted to start today because
it's like
um I think you're probably one of the
unique most unique hackers in our space
you know obviously bug bounty has a lot
of a lot of um variance in the people
that are participating in it by nature
of what it is you know anybody can
participate there's no there's no um
limits on that but to see someone do be
a medical doctor and also do bug Bounty
is pretty pretty mind-blowing um so I'm
wondering you know which one of those
did you have interest in first and how
did you you know hop how did you
simultaneously become very good at both
of these things uh thanks you make me a
little bit shter but
uh so to start with I think most hackers
start when they are young it's it's it's
it's the the State of Mind of like how
does this work how
to find the boundaries of this thing
that that I'm using if it's a computer
game or some software at school so yeah
it all started when was really young say
12 years old 13 years old when you start
building websites or start figing out
figuring out how internet works so I
can't say oh I was first a doctor and
then then a hacker no I think I was
starting real young there and I was
developing websites and trying to
understand how search engine
optimizations
work um but if you have to ask me
nowadays what am I I will tell you on
the do and theing say that is something
that can
into my
life about six years ago so before that
time um I did med school and during med
school you have to earn some money
because it's expensive you have to live
on your own and in some big cities so
that's when I started to BU websites
e-commerce things startups so I was
responsible for some big auctioning
website in the mland some big crowding
interesting so I learned from the F SE
developer perspective how to handle a
lot of data pii data and how to do it a
little bit secure was all PHP at the
time so that's a challenge but still you
learn a lot and um after that uh uh I
went uh went to work as a street doctor
three days a week two days a week
startups and then at one moment I began
a GP and that is a special parading of
three years just searching you need six
years as a Dy two years in Newland and
they forbid me to do any Sidekicks any
any
external jobs because they say we pay
your training so we want you to focus on
it which is okay but a hacker never
stops thinking as a hacker
so at one Mo moment mid of my trainings
I went to to this um I can say this
group where all the uh all the doctors
come together that they are in the
training and my supervisor was there as
well and I asked him like hey is there a
possibility that I could do some yeah
variation of Chess of Chess matches
online and if I win them then I might
earn a pricee it's not like a guaranteed
income and is that is that an option can
do Sports actually and they were like
yeah yeah Internet Sports that's all but
it exists and some sort of Chess yeah
some sort of Chess so they gave me
permission to do that and that what's
actually good by this so I saw the
national some some young guy Shan is his
name shout out to Forin if he listened
to the podcast I'm not sure I've never
met him in person ferin was a book bar
there and on the national television he
he mentioned like yeah yeah some people
say uh b b is hard but I earn 10K a
weekend for finding bucks and I was like
this guy so you how does he do that so
that was a moment for me to introduce
this to my supervisors and and I said
yeah that's given a ride so that's when
it all started so so you know at this
time you're you're in training for this
for this um for being a GP and you're
you're not allowed to do side gigs but
you figure out a way to make this side
gig a you know a game a a gamble you
know a risk maybe um that has some
monetary incentive all right thinking
like a hacker I love it dude um and and
I just I want wonder I wonder this um I
wonder why you decided to go down the
route of medicine when you were clearly
passionate about hacking and tinkering
and computer stuff for this whole
duration as well right like typically
what what most people will do most
people have have a hard enough time
coming up with one thing that they're
passionate about um and and really going
ham at that but you you identified you
know you went the medical route and the
and the hacking route so what what what
made you do that instead of just picking
and sticking with it or picking you know
medicine and sticking with that yeah so
the honest answer is uh I was 17 years
old and I was almost done with the last
year in high school so that's the moment
where you go to different University to
have a look around so I went to this
introduction course on artificial
intelligence actually and I went there
with one of my best friends who um later
on ended up ended up at open AI as one
of their first employees wow super proud
on him super proud on him so but um I
went with him there and and I sat down
in this big big theater and then where
all the students come together and then
the person in front of the theater
started the introduction and said I'm so
happy this year of the 400 interested
people four females sign up and this was
a moment of chis to me it was like okay
wait John you're quite good in computers
you're not really interested in girls
but you now might sign up for a world
with which your only meals and that was
a problem at the time these days it's
it's less of a thing and that's that's
super good but I'm an old guy I'm 37 so
back in the day 18 years ago this was a
problem so this was when I went back to
the drawing board and I was like okay if
I want to live in a world where bony
dies they will become my best friends
and I will have a great time but I might
prefer a more diverse world to to to
work in for the last for the upcoming 40
years and so I started thinking about
what was the most interesting thing in
high school stuff that I can't really
understand and I would love to learn
more about because this is the moment in
life that I can do that and besides
computers and hacking and Ai and that
sort of stuff I figured out biology is
is the thing I had such a good teacher
at the time that it was so inspiring
it's was one of those those people you
meet in life you everyone got a few of
them but this biology teacher um made me
decide to do med school and I was quite
lucky since you have to sign up for med
school you do interviews and um it was a
lottery at the time so I had to be lucky
but um I was placed in in some
University in Amsterdam and start doing
that and it it was the best choice Maybe
in my young youth because you learn so
much not only about biology but also
about ethics about communication about
uh what matters in life and till this
day I'm I'm super grateful that I can do
this work because it shows you how short
life is how important it is to enjoy
every good minute of it but also help
others out and and share your your luck
share your insights and and just try to
make the best of it so yeah that that's
a little bit of the the background of
that that that makes sense I mean I I
definitely felt that draw as well just
as I don't know that I've talked about
this on the Pod before but um you know
back when I was in college and they up
until I guess two years um past when you
start college in the US you can still
sort of change and and go to a different
route and um even though I was really
into like computer science and and
hacking stuff in college um there I was
a part of a leadership program and the
some of the most of the other people in
the leadership program were Med students
and so they were they were talking to me
and my grades were really good as
particularly in chemistry um and they
were like Justin you know a a a like
very programmatic thinking Computer
Science Guy with uh you know really good
grades in chemistry would make a really
killer med school application and I'm
like I sat there for a second and I was
like man I would love to help people you
know I would love to be able to to you
know be a part of of saving people's
life or or um you know get giving people
their health back and I was I was close
man I was very close to going down that
route so I definitely when I when I see
you on the scene I'm like this is what
this is what could have been
potentially you can still become maybe
one I'm not sure in your country how
that works but in that school when I was
there there were also people of 30 plus
uh 40 even there uh it cost a little bit
more money but it's a possibility and
I'm sure you you will be a great doctor
and with you there's plenty of b b
Hunters actually that think like doctors
but they're not aware that they do since
what what you guys do what we do as B
Hunters we do Recon well this doctor
where you're sitting in front of is also
doing recon on you and it's not going to
pull a thff on you uh on Thousand TRS
and and draw withdraw all your blood and
check it for everything no but because
you will end up with too much false
positives or collapsing patient just
like a server that is crashing because
of doing too much Recon and so your
pinpoint you do the specific nuclear
templates on this human body and then
you get some signal back and then you
starts figuring out what's going on and
you're connecting the dots that's what b
b Hunters do connecting dots and finding
risk groups um in other words uh certain
types of surfaces uh that are running
trying to figure out systemic problems
that exist in all different humans yeah
that's what we do as well as Doctor
systemic issues as B we look for
um uh sandbox Chrome instances making
screenshots and then breaking out of
them doctors do the same they we are
thinking like oh wait a minute this
disease looks like that disease and it
exists everywhere so we need to poke
into those sand boxes of the human body
and see what's going on so so there's so
many similarities I'm sure if we if we
confer a lot of audience tomorrow into
doctors and that will be great we be a
pry that'd be pretty cool and I think I
think there's a lot about pug Bounty
that can feel pretty like I don't know
like green hat right like you're just in
it for the money in in some scenarios
bug bounty hunters are notoriously like
that and I think it's refreshing to see
your take on on on bug Bounty combined
with you know this whole ethics piece as
well because I know that that plays a
big part with you um you know in your in
your perception of the situation um from
a doctor perspective right you know you
you have taken an oath to try to care
for these patients and and in a similar
way I know you're applying a lot of that
that technical um stuff to the medicine
space trying to protect the patients
trying to protect the doctors and that
sort of thing um and and I think you
know there's there's power in in the bug
Bounty world as well you know being able
to find and exploit these
vulnerabilities and you want to use that
for for positive means to try to make
the world safer and uh and and care for
the the people in it yeah it's a part I
forgot in the um it's
during the training of becoming a GP one
of the main reasons for also trying the
book bount thing is um is the thing you
actually just uh described I'm trained
as a doctor to see if some treatment or
some tablets or some injection has more
benefits than risks so I only want to to
give you well good treatments and don't
cause you harm and I'm not trained to
assess computer systems as a doctor but
I prescribe them nonstop I give you
earnings I send forms to you I invite
you to my portals I connect systems and
so I'm not trained at that and I have to
trust the blue eyes of all those people
doing a great job on putting
certificates on all those applications
and infrastructure the Prov is ining and
I want to to see myself if it's really
working and that's schol to to to go to
is since is the place where you learn
actually what happens what what what is
the the bugs of Tomorrow what are the
bugs of today and what to look for so I
don't say uh certificates and and isos
and whatever is is not good no it's part
of your your your way to to defend def
to defend yourself but the Lost Resort
is book bounties and yeah you need to be
able to think out of the box poke from
different direction s and um I think pen
testing is limited Often by scope and
book Val
is still a little bit limited by scope
but more and more you the Scopes are
widening up and that that is perfect
because then you can connect the dots
again think like a real hacker and see
how this patient or doctor F actually or
the other weak groups we have M and
there's good money so my disclosure I'm
always honest about that I earned 95% of
my money with B money so only 5% is is
with being a doctor and stuff like that
and it's not to a number I tell people
to show off no it's just my conflicts of
interest so I've got a big interest in
in uh also pushing the book bodies but I
think for a good cause in healthcare
it's it's almost non-existing well and
and enlighten me a little bit about how
this works in European countries because
in the US like doctors normally make a
pretty good amount of money um it's one
of the higher paying things and and I
think that's probably a lot because of
the stupid stupid system we have over
here where everything in healthcare is
ridiculously inflated right um and not
to say that doctors shouldn't make a lot
of money I think they should because
they're doing a big service but I think
there's there's also this aspect where I
believe in European countries it's a
little bit different where being like a
doctor is perceived more as like a as a
as a public Public Service sort of thing
um yeah sort of most doctors and lens
work for the the public health as we say
so it's you pay you're forced to to pay
for insurance healthcare insurance
that's by law thing you need to do and
then you can also access this Healthcare
and um doctors earn good in the ne no no
no Mis no misunderstandings about that
but to give a figure it's like if you're
a well earning doctor it's 100K Max
and maybe there are Exceptions there but
so it's still a lot of money but for
working five days a week being vable to
all different types of lawsuits and um
having
to be always on top of stuff and and
don't make mistakes that's that's
putting yourself at risk too you know
you're dealing with a lot of sick people
you know you you're G to get get
sick yeah I imagine so dude that must
have been that must have been terrifying
so yeah that that definitely makes sense
and um yeah that that uh that it makes
sense that you would be out earning that
in bug Bounty a lot because uh the way
that I've seen it you've been you've
been really crushing it um and let's uh
let's go ahead and and pivot into that
Arena now and I I want to pick your
brain on um you know youro approach to
bug Bounty programs and that sort of
thing I also want to swing back around
to some of how the way
um the the way that you approach some of
this health related stuff in bug Bounty
as well you know making sure you're keep
keeping your body energized and and how
you've been able to continue for such a
long amount of time in Buck Bounty um
with with high performance with that but
let's let's jump over to the the um
hacking stuff uh real quick hey guys our
sponsor project Discovery has dropped a
new tool in collaboration with Google's
own mandian team called TLD finder okay
picture the SubFinder but for top level
domains need I say anymore check it
out okay so we can talk about the fact
that Amazon is your primary program um
and you've been pretty much exclusively
hacking on Amazon for the past what six
years five six years yeah my initial
idea was to get brid quickly on Amazon
from scroll. am you can still go to this
website I think it's still online I hope
my SSL working and if you go there you
see an animating gift of how the site
used to work and what I did is I created
some front end some laptab uh backend
services that um misused in the end the
API of the Amazon app and created some
Pinterest look on Amazon so no UI
distractions just you can enter
something boom you saw the products so
that's when I thought like okay if I do
this put referral links on them I get
rich easily because I get this affiliate
thing of 10% of everything that is not
in the next days this fils miserably
because after four days I was banned
from the affiliate program on Amazon but
during yeah because yeah you should um
embed their content on your website and
not create content that is solely their
content that was one of the real thing
and okay can happen I learned a lot I
learned a lot about JavaScript
Frameworks and about LDA and micro
servic and stuff like that and scill it
up in such way that it does not burn a
lot of money but during that time I had
to detect the Android app of Amazon
and while doing that I found some uh
endpoint that was funable to reflect the
DSs and by today that's still the only
Amazon report that is disclosed on
medium I think so if you Google it you
can find it there some really really
fancy payload with
uh GS fck is I think the name of the
payload generator um but but um I found
some books so I emailed them like hey
there's an EXs there um B me so you
might be able to unban me but okay I
understand it's in your terms and
condition so fair game but you need to
fix this back so they replied back thank
you and bye and then it was silent for
one year and then suddenly some guy uh
emailed me from the uh amazon security
department how he was one of the
founders of the book bount program of
Amazon and he was like Jonathan do you
want to become part of some experiment
of us as experience
tell me what what type of experience
yeah we want to create a group to into
trust you're you could be one of them I
love that name by the way like it's so
dramatic it's like uh
okay is brilliant and love and like yeah
this makes sense if I go to the bar and
in a bar and I tell them girl hey I'm
Jonathan I'm part of KN and the trust
I'm a KN for finding best on on a
website but
um so I said yes and that was the moment
that I started reporting B to them
earning points and with those points
gift cards so so so you were I guess I I
didn't know this you were actually one
of the preliminary people one of the
first people to be a part of Amazon's
spook Bounty programs and was that was
that something they were just running
privately at that point were they
running it through hacker one were they
how that working B Crow bug crowd yeah
so so that's where I started and uh yeah
TR trying to find more xss and all the O
STP 10 bucks
uh learning a lot of stuff and that's
the moment where at some point I had 100
points and with 100 points you earned
the
certificate and oh oh snap okay here we
go and this certificate there's
something really important I received it
I was really proud I open up the box and
I let me try to find it I got it
somewhere behind go see if you can find
it yeah yeah because there's something
fun
there yeah I found it nice
so there was a moment I I put it yeah
that I re this thing and have a look at
the
logo yeah yeah but if you look closely
it's number two it's not number one so I
was like who is number one guy number
two what
is and that was the moment I start doing
some some Al end on the internet having
a look around putting it on Twitter
looked on LinkedIn and I found out
there's a guy
named number one and I was like holy
[__] who is this guy and what did he do
so I got in touch with him and we had a
immediately a great son like oh no you
found this book I also found i j you
there and um but but what we discovered
that only maybe 1% of the we found we
duped each other but the
99% we did not so somehow we did
different things there so we had some
say six seven months where we raced each
other in a chge and then he taught me
then I taught him and then he taught me
and then T him
and at one moment we figured out it
might be more fun if we collab here and
and just join forces since we all we
both do a different
but we might uh have unfinished bucks
that we can finish for each other and so
that that's how all how it all started
um and and so at this point I mean
you've connected with with Zano that's
great right and uh and so I'm wondering
here like what is you've only had your
experience with just the Amazon program
right like you haven't been poking
around on other bug Bounty programs so I
mean is that is that have you did once
you started getting money out of it like
where you're like okay maybe I should
look around at this other bug Bounty
thing and start going to these other
programs or were you always just so
locked into Amazon um at the time I was
more busy with discovering new
techniques and and Amazon was helping
that me with that but it was also more
so if you look on my medium blog you'll
see disclosures about Ikea it's all
different sort yeah Ikea that's right
and that was not about money it was also
it was primarily about learning your
stuff and also
uh um just discovering how it all worked
the respons on disclosure the Amazon in
in the beginning that was all earning
points so say the first six months that
was um so you were just doing it for fun
yeah it was fun but I got gift boxes
with with Kindles and at one point I got
invited to to death so that was the the
the first big surprise I got there so
yeah I went there with my brother I
booked a hotel room got an email back
from the Amazon team please book a
better hotel room I sent the Ino again
so I book a better hotel room got there
and and that feels nice yeah felt like a
celebrity so I went to Las Vegas with my
little brother there and um had a great
time at DES and hang around with the
Amazon team which was super small was
how why and some other people we bunker
and um yeah that's when I also start
doing more and and also look around a
little bit so I had some mic maybe a few
bucks and sure my focus on Amazon all
the time because the scope is so big and
so
complex yeah so that that's kind of what
I want to double click into a little bit
more as well is like you know I think
there are very few programs on which
it's feasible for you to spend six years
and still be finding bugs out the wazu I
mean you guys found over or around a
hundred bugs together you and Zano at
this last event which is
unbelievable and um and so I mean do you
think that the biggest thing that Amazon
has going in its favor for that sort of
Engagement is the fact that the scope is
just so massive and you're constantly
finding new applications or is it the
speed at which they're putting code or
the the interactions with the the
researchers what what what is Amazon
doing that has been able to keep your
attention for six years they have a
realistic scope in my opinion so their
attack surfice is quite big they
understand that X STX service is quite
big one of
their um goals are is to to be aware of
the new bucks as soon as possible so
that's why they have good inter good
interactions with me as a researcher um
I know their weak spots so I monitor for
the weak spots um I know what they find
important with the stuff they don't find
important and yeah it's it's a it's a
good program to me because
um it's so complex we're in one of the
biggest companies in the world all
digital with tons of employees tons of
talented people trying new
Innovations and with every Innovation
there's some risk of something going
wrong and that's where we jump in as
bount Hunters to make them aware of the
risks and um um yeah there's how it
never stops how are you how are you
aware of this Innovation are you
monitoring for like are you watching
them in the news do you have like
monitoring set up at the specific
application Level for new code being
pushed or does it just make itself
apparent to you because you're living in
that ecosystem yeah yeah you just need
to be in the ecosystem and sometimes
order a product it's just like if you
want to hack on Netflix you should watch
Netflix movies and if you want to hack
on Amazon you should order every once in
a while some product so do you do you
use Amazon I mean like is that is that
something that that you use often okay
yeah I bought to use the product yeah do
you do you um do do you deal with
fatigue on the same Target like like
where you just don't really want to look
at these types of requests anymore or
like anything like that or is it is it
pretty fresh
um long term no because I take paes so
for example after the last Live Hack
event I took a pass of now I think full
week and some more days so
that's really important to me because I
also have a lot of other
responsibilities and so that's just
recover time if you run a marathon you
should recover from this Marathon there
are only a few that can keep running
those marathons but I'm not part of that
um I collab a lot so it's not money I
chase it's not the points I chase it's
the fun I chase and the excitement of
finding new types of bugs or learn and
stuff so you don't get fatigue if you
learn something new even though you
focusing on the right things yeah and if
you don't find books but you learn
something new then you still have some
achievement there um yes that's maybe
one of the take homes I want to share in
your podcast don't depend too much on b
b it there are some people who do it
full-time which I'm looking too and I
oh that's amazing that you can do that
but from from my perspective I got four
of three different four different other
jobs and that's also part of my
personality income three or four
different other jobs oh my
gosh but that that also makes it easier
that if one thing collapse or or you get
too much fatigue from it then you slow
down on that one and and try to figure
out with the other jobs or the other
stuff you do it could be a sport could
be some sidekick you do defending stuff
and not they're starting their own
startups at one point or their own
products I think that's that's really
smart to do because if you do book
bounties for six years full time I'm not
sure if I could do that I don't think I
do so so for you the the reason you've
been able to do this so long in in in a
performant way is because you are not
focusing on the the nitty-gritty pieces
aspects of it and when you get tired
you're taking breaks and you're not
putting stress on yourself to perform in
the bug Bounty world yeah you're just
chasing the fun aspect of it right is
that is that accurate yeah that's
accurate and I was super lucky though
that I had some wild card for the first
Amazon uh event which was a virtual one
in during Co and I managed to win that
one so yeah then out of nothing year
first event you win this mph thing and
then you're like oh this was the top
prize I could win okay that that's good
so I don't have to stress anymore so
yeah that you feel a little bit more
secure in your in your position in that
that world as well that's good Z shano
got the first the first little
certificate but Jonathan Bowman you know
got the got the mvh with all these
prizes also I think this one is
uh it it is alsoo is one so we during y
fense we we collap fully I think I might
just add some more points on the first
life AC because I found some chain that
we popped and he he helped me out to to
to do but I had some some more points so
the yeah I can say if you look at that
from that perspective I might be more
MGH but from my from my perspective he
he's he's like similar you guys you guys
have very a very legendary collaboration
set up in place and and that's kind of
what I want to stick to next is like you
know how transparently are you guys
sharing all of the techniques and stuff
because at the end of the day there's a
lot of money on the line here yeah and I
know for sure that you have come up with
a technique that that you know didn't
take any input from him and and vice
versa and and then you guys have to
decide okay you know if I give this to
Zano or if I give this to bman Dr Bowman
then you know there's going to be some
vulnerabilities that they find that I
won't be able to just get and Report
myself so I mean what does that
trade-off look like for you and and um
how have you managed that over the past
six years of
collaboration yeah well we do a lot of
research together so there's no there's
no no problem there if you share stuff
no and it's also super fancy what we do
so it's not like super high technical
complex things now I sometimes go a
little bit more deeper in in some new
new techniques and at the same time he
he also goes deeper every once in a
while and if I tell him I I will pause
for a month I'm very happy if he report
about finding some chain I created
together with him and I'm and sometimes
we share it a little bit it's it's just
sinking in with each other like hey how
does that feel yeah feels well okay you
go hunt on this thing I I'll focus on
this other life hack event and have a
good one and then by the end of the week
he made a [__] ton of good money and I'm
at his Live Hack and super proud on some
some some some some high uh ctss buck
that took me 10 days to develop and and
and not for the money but just for the
for the for the SS well
and yeah you should money I think that
that is the thing and if you sink in
enough with each other and both are on
the same page on that and then
you yeah that stuff is not then the
money will come too I mean at the end of
the day you're you're you're you're
performing better together and you're
collaborating and you are sharing that
knowledge and um you know I think you
said in an interview with hacker one
that I watched in in prep for this
podcast that a lot of the advancements
that have been made in the medical
industry have been made because of
Relentless sharing of information and
and trying to get that information out
to everyone so that people can save
lives and help people live more quality
lives yeah and I think you know you've
applied something similar here with with
this collaboration where you guys share
and that just continues to compound and
compound and compound um yeah I think
that just a good summary and and the
best thing is that relationship should
go over any virtual internet points or
money or whatever
and that's just in a relationship with
with with a partner in in real
life Al I speak with Sean maybe as much
as with for Renee my
girlfriend funny thing sometime is the
first person I speak to and by the end
of the day the last person I speak to is
already sleeping but um and yeah you
share a lot of stuff in life
and I I don't have to worry and that's
maybe a good other take home thing is
try to find a better on your partner a
lot of people I and um try to build up a
trust relation with with the other
person think in and if you feel like hey
this feels uncomfortable just bring it
up and say hey what do you think about
that or should we communication yes
communication and also I work as a
doctor that's that's main the main thing
is communication about if you do stuff
stuff wrong if I did something wrong
yeah I tell people I did I I messed up I
did with a good good reason but it was
not good yeah let's fix it so have there
have there been you know in in this
commitment to communication and you say
hey does this feel good with you does
this feel good with you have there been
times where you guys have said no that
doesn't feel good and no that doesn't
feel good and and you know you guys have
a disagreement that you have to resolve
at more at length really it's been it's
been pretty smooth yeah yeah but that
that that is some luck in life that you
run into people that are not Ed or not
in in in the game for fame or money no
of course it pays the bills so yeah I
yeah of course that's a thing but by the
end of the day you yeah but as you said
you are more together if you if you look
for the long perspectives and um it also
does not burn you out it yeah there's a
lot of benefits there lots of lots of
Pros to that so so swinging back around
to the Amazon program itself one of the
things you had here in the list uh in
the doc is is that Amazon one of the
things that makes Amazon agre program is
they have consistent payouts for certain
bugs bug types um can you talk a little
bit about what that why you really like
that and how that makes Amazon an
amazing
program so for all the people who work
for program listening to your podcast
the one of the the the key things you
need to try to achieve it consistency
and that's also an hard part like how do
you apply cpss how do you rate certain
bucks um how do you deal with some xss
that someone already reported but you
got a new report where there's a payload
that does different stuff there or
approve account takeovers or stuff like
that um and that's something that you
can do as a program where you to give
the same answer multiple times in the in
a row about certain book types and be
predictable um take feedback from
researchers like hey this might be odd
that this payout is so much lower or how
do you feel about that or would it make
sense if we change this uh would that be
more interesting to you
and that conversation if that keeps
going and the leadership is there all Al
continuing the previous
leaderships um that makes it a program
consistent and less stressful as a
researcher because the last thing we
like to see is that one day you get say
onek then 3K down 4K down 1K and then
you start asking yourself like what's
the difference is the weather and it
feels like our our work is discredited
as well like sometimes you could be
really proud of a bug and then you're
like ah wow you really don't see that
and and that's disappointing yeah so so
that that is the perspective in need
from a b bound Hunter you you feel some
yeah you want the reward and you want to
be a consistent reward because otherwise
she might doubt like hey this is less
good
or yeah that's that's important I think
that's probably one of I I have to say I
think that's probably one of the reasons
that Amazon has been able to keep so
many anchor hackers like you and and
Zano is that they they have their their
thing and they stick to it and they pay
the bugs and that sort of thing and you
can become very consistent then and and
you can really understand the threat
model of an organization and of an
application very thoroughly and that
just feels it just clicks right you know
you when when you when you finally when
you get these bugs paid and they're paid
the same way time and time again you can
really feel like you've got Mastery of a
specific Set uh of a of a program or a
set of applications yeah you understand
way better what they find important to
them and um also you understand more or
how to report certain stuff or what what
is necessary for them to see in a report
that makes them like okay this this
needs to to get priority because by the
end of the day we don't want um we we
want the proper cdss or rating for a bu
because that helps also in getting stuff
fixed well this more an ethical
perspective but uh I think it's an
important one um so sometimes I'm I'm
finding some some downgrading by of a bu
only because well it earns maybe a
little bit more money but to be sure
that's on the top of their list to get
six and that everyone got a true
understanding of the true of the real
impact um and and last thing about that
is that um it's super important with big
companies like Amazon but also all the
other big uh big companies on the stock
markets is that you you tend to have
people moving around the company every
three four years so there's a thing that
if you're work for a certain big company
you need to have some career path and
that's a hard thing because we as B
Hunters have to deal with different
phases different teams new new
leadership Etc and that's something that
Amazon achieved quite well is to to keep
the the mindset the same as it was six
years ago the same sort of people are
working in their leadership
positions um and what what I observed
now doing book bounties for a while is
that you see programs changing so so
fast into great programs turning into
programs with a lot of problems and it
might be money because less budget might
be changing of people working for the
teams so H try to get some some
permanent positions seniors yeah people
who understand our position as a
researcher but also understand the
internal problems and then then you have
a great progam yeah I think that's super
important even even in just the you know
year and some change that I've been
running this podcast year and a half
I've I've said some great stuff about
programs and then you know come back a
year later and it's like completely
different experience because of turnover
and because of changes within the
organization so that consistency I think
is huge from a from a People level as
well and is something that I think
extends Beyond just the realm of
security as well we I think it's sort of
a problem with tech in general right now
is that there's so much turnover and so
much job hopping to climb the ladder and
that sort of thing where people just
need to pay more money and and you know
or have a a consistent schedule to go up
so that these people don't have to jump
around from job to job to job and
relearn a new system every like two or
three years exactly yeah yeah it's it's
it's intense man um I think with that I
think we'll move into some of the more
technical aspects uh I'm very excited
that you have agreed to um release some
of the information about this server
side template injection vulnerability on
sender um with us on the Pod today so um
Thanks for for for doing that can you
talk a little bit about that bug and um
how you found it and how it can be
exploited so file s is quite interesting
piece of sofware it's used for the
last well maybe 15 years I think it's
it's really old when I was in in
University doing that school I used it
and it's used in the nland all
University and other uh colleges to send
around files because uh we had we did
not have file send of um we transfer and
the other uh um Solutions at the time so
University figured out let's open stor
to ourselves and we call file sender so
you can find it on get it's a quite
interesting tool since well you can
connect um some um some uh SSO some
logging thing so students can
and then people can upload stuff and you
can send someone else a link or or an
email with the the contents um and it
works quite well um but in the recent
years they also um added some extra
surfaces behind it so S3 is supported
now so that's that's good for
storage AWS layers of complexity as well
though yeah yeah true
that um and I
um have good contact with in the cyers
of the infos uh community of the
universities in the nland we got some
sort of one internet service provider
girl serf amazing people working there
and they reached out to me like hey John
we are trying we are thinking of rolling
out a full new version of file Center
file Center tree and we did a lot of
pests already we think it's it's quite
secure but can you have a final look at
it
and quite being quite busy with the uh
with the live hacky fans I had it
somewhere on my list but I to be honest
forgot forgot about it so I got a
reminder from one of the the people
working there and like John you should
have a look really do it do it so I was
like okay let's do that so I asked them
like hey do you have any amazing that
you fit this in dude amazing that you
make this happen I don't understand
continue sorry yeah and so I was like uh
can you spin up a machine where it's
running so I can first do some black box
before Ive deep into the the source code
and what we do as back B Hunters we look
for un all stuff first because that um
yeah has the highest impact so what
types of stuff can we find and quite
quickly I figured out there were certain
error messages and those error messages
uh came up within the Euros s base 64
coding and I decoded that and I figured
out hey there's some templating
stuff going on there is I saw some
template codes
but then I tried to think like why did I
do that and the reason for that was they
have different University different
logos different temp of designs so in
emails they want to give different uh uh
logos for example um and also to um yeah
to to expose like where's the the actual
um base Earl and what's the base Earl
and stuff like that
and I could see that I could manipulate
manipulate the error message off and
then I just started looking in the code
in one of your previous podcast it's
like where's the request was was one of
the main main changing things where's
the request game yeah yeah I love that
was where the error came from and so
that was the thing I tried to do so I
just literally download the zip file
from GI up up it open it up in F Cod and
just did console Shi F and search all
the files for um the the the error
message actually that was
there so after a few clicks I figured
out where is the loop that tries to
replace those um uh those templates uh
texts in error messages figured out
where it was so no complex debuggers
with PHP storm or something no just just
looking in the code and I thought there
was also a
config uh a config template variable
that was used for the um for the Puffs
the server Puffs actually so where could
I download where where should it write
temporary files or something like
that the next moment you do when you
find that you immediately look for what
other confict variables are existing and
then you figure out oh wait a minute my
SQL database user and password so I I
tried to do that and I saw the username
and password and I was like oops isn't
that
good dude how how far are you into this
assessment like is this like you just s
minutes checked it out for oh my God
please just getting an error and I'm
like hey Bas 64 as soon as we see Bas 64
is like extrem on the skin we understand
like there is something going on there
and we need to get you a cream and in
this situation we need to look at your
this code why should you is very sex4 so
that was the first first thing and then
uh yeah it was it was quite easy to
figure out and um this new version also
has S3 support um so I saw they like to
dump the sprits and exis key of at S3
bucket full access to the to the file
system so I reported back to them I'm
like hey there's a problem with your
version three uh you might need to have
a double look extra look at it
and
then a few hours later I was like but if
it's in the latest version why is it not
in the currently used version so I
looked into the source code and i' you
got this thing get blame where you can
see how old he commit is I love that and
that this commit was 10 years old and I
was like oh [__] oh [__] this thing is
already hanging around for 10 years and
oh man so I looked into the production
version of the the one used by my
University and I figured out that they
were formulable I could just see the the
S3 key and ex to all stuff so I tried to
log in at on the booket just to prove
impact yes I could access it so that was
quite a complex problem since this
software is used in a lot of places in
especially um education but also some
some healthcare organizations are using
it some um big governmental
organizations are using it uh yeah then
you have to start to do the responsible
disclosure and they did an amazing job
since it's all open source things so
it's all like people doing this in as
volunteers are you are you working with
the file sender team directly at this
point are you working with that
Collective of okay nice yeah yeah and
they were luckily enough they were
together with some conference in Paris
so so they sent up a call quite quickly
I got them true to understand where the
books are are existing then they try to
figure out how to H patch this that was
quite hard because it's a templating
thing so it might break a lot um so they
start creating
patches um they start monitoring if the
books were abused that because it might
be a zero day already discovered by
someone else
sure
um and then the part two of the Thun of
the fun yeah it's it's fun for me as a b
Bounty Hunter not yeah I don't think
they would describe that day as fun no
no no no no I mean that's also the
hardest part is being a doctor sometimes
you feel so excited finding this rare
disease but you have to understand at
the same time there's someone in front
of you not happy so you learn how to
cope with excitement on moments where
that that just go but here um part two
of the excitement comes was the moment
they start developing the fix this GI
commit
book was published and super interesting
from the TR right was I think so yeah so
long story short every fork in a repo
is uh even if the fork is hidden the
commits might be also hidden but if you
know the HH of the commit some piece of
it that is unique they can still view it
somehow that it is security through
obscurity um so I figured out like hey
would be fun if they start trying to
patch this buck and commit on the public
repo and um lo and behold that's what
happened so so that's what I did so I
reached out to uh lopin and uh to Triple
themselves like hey I want to try this
tool how to do that and lopin being a
great talented hacker already figured
out pipelines and stuff so he helped me
a little bit there and uh I run this
script on some some little lenux box for
I think two hours three hours in total
and I found the commit they made to
patch this thing so way dude so I had to
reach out back to them again like hey
dudes be aware that at this moment a lot
of gift commits of get up commits are
being uh scraped
and if it's not known this patch there
is a risk that this patch is found by
someone and also the zero day is exposed
or one day whatever
so then were're like no you
again no get out of
here that's great but the way how you
handle it is also that is academics
that's why I work one day a week in
academics is is there are also
scientists and are also like oh [__]
this is cool how does that work so well
that's good I'm glad that they that they
appreciate it because it it is it is
pretty cool stuff um and I was looking
at you know when you sent me over this
this 10-year-old commit or whatever I
was kind of looking at the way that they
patched it and stuff and it's a little
bit of an odd thing that they're doing
it looks like here right because
essentially the way that this
vulnerability was working if I
understand correctly was um you know
there would be an exception page that
would be generated and then you would
pass a b64 encoded you know in exception
string or something like that into that
page and then that would get
concatenated with a template and then
that template would be rendered right um
but they're still doing it looks like it
seems like they've moved that user
controlled portion of that input into uh
some some um something different so it's
not getting concatenated into the
template there they've Associated it
with the session but it still looks like
they're dynamically rendering templates
themselves right like like in and it
it's different from actually taking a
template and uh you know rendering it
it's dynamically creating a template
then that you will then render which I
think is just a little bit of a weird
way of doing things um so I I wonder I
wonder if there are more server side
template injection bugs on this on this
software because it I mean like you said
it's pretty widely used I believe um so
I think there could be more more things
there are do you have any plans to
continue looking at it further oh yeah
for sure yeah yeah yeah yeah I I tried
to break it I was not able to break the
patch uh if one of your listeners is
please reach out with their teams um to
the search uh behind F Center I think is
also the main R post if you open it
there there's ways to get in touch with
the the
owners and if you got struggles always
feel free also to reach out to me but um
file center.org it is I think file
center.org
yeah that's the way you should go so um
then contact so yeah I if someone finds
some there something there there might
be still a way to do this but uh
I'm not experienced enough I think to do
that so help the research World help
academics yeah and and you don't earn
big money that's the thing but you earn
some you know the thing of doing good
for human mankind and maybe some
stickers some T-shirts whatever maybe
some stickers or t-shirts that's good um
are you you're planning on doing the
blog post as well in conjunction with
this pod right you're going to drop that
or is it going to be okay so so we'll
have a we'll have a blog post down in
the description I'll uh I'll call that
out now um when we release this episode
um and then we'll we'll probably put the
the PC somewhere up here on the screen
or something like that as well so that
you guys can understand um exactly
what's happening but um I was reading
through some of your other bugs as well
Jonathan and I actually see you know a a
a trend of serverside template injection
which is just really a weak bug for me
like I I've only ever found serers side
template injection like once or twice um
and and so what um what are you doing
that is making you find these serverside
template injections I know that in one
of your articles you mentioned a custom
burp scanning profile that helps with
that um but what are are you just SP
spraying the payloads around or thinking
about it from a templating perspective
what's going on there
um I try to use the ver active scanner
in such a way that it only scans for
useful stuff and I think you can there's
a lot of trainings around on how to use
burp uh and how to use all the different
options but um I think the most
important part is how to use the active
scanner in such a way that is useful and
there are a few steps I always take
first I look at the Target I try to
figure out what coding language is
behind it sometimes there are multiple
ones it's like a reverse proxy so on an
end point and sometimes one and
especially with the old coding languages
like Pearl and and the ancient ones
there you want to be sure that it's part
of your active scan and often uh bers
turn them off the active scanner because
they get your band on nakami or whatever
is too too noisy um and they forget to
turn it on or if they turn it on they
only turn on EX us
or server interaction types of stuff but
if you to on the the template injections
uh the pro code injection and and that's
what it's called in the in the active
scan then you might end up with books
that other people missed out and so
there's there's an interesting bck post
um rce I found on aold one of the
biggest food companies in the world
a and the only way I could find that was
because I had my bur configure to also
scan for Pearl code injections and they
get some some payload that does um yeah
doesn't sleep or prove it there is code
injection to show impact you need to
start coding BR which I can't do myself
so it's so so terrible so
terrible so so now you you need to
figure out which chat your old
friends to or old
friends to to get that Savage yeah and
then then yeah you end up with good
stuff but um that is a way another way
is um try to understand how there uh how
the templates are rendered so for
certain targets Amazon for example I
know exactly what types of strings they
use for templates and for a lot of other
Target tiles and and you can
discover by looking at uh not properly
rendered p for example and that's you
need to be lucky there so look in yourap
look for for the the generic template
types of how you write the template
codes angle brackets and yeah and then
figure out okay those are the the the
the the angle brackets they use okay
this is an example what actually also
get Runners a proper variable uh and
then you might put that in your word
list for um for your own cust SCS so
that's that's way to go I know I noticed
also in this write up that you did with
um a hold USA that you first brute
forced for parameters on this specific
endpoint and then you did the did the
scan and and that scan uncovered the the
Pearl injection is that I mean is that
something that you you have a part of
your flow pretty often is identifying
each individual endpoint and then brute
forcing parameters on those endpoints
correct y yeah the challenge for us as
bman Huns is to discover inch
functionality and
um Cy string
parameters form uh parameters that are
not mentioned in the JavaScript not
mentioned anywhere but are doing
something on the code that's where
that's where you want to look because
other people miss that out and so yeah
you need to have some flow where are you
are you using param Miner for that or
are you mostly just using Intruder like
you are in this in this article I've got
a hate relationship with par Miner I
hate a lot of things so I turn it on as
everyone and I turn it off after 20
seconds and then I turn it on again and
then I turn it off because it never
stops uh right if someone can fix a
version of parer that actually behaves
and doesn't go Rogue and everything that
will be super
helpful what do you mean by go Rogue are
you talking about how like it adds like
cash cash poisoning or like canaries or
whatever all the different requests or
what what what are you talking about I
might need to read the manual yes I
might take the wrong boxes there um but
often for me it slows down it hangs so
that's that's maybe the thing the on
Amazon I would not recommend you to use
fire Min for example will get you a l of
headaches um gotcha and so what you're
looking for in those scenarios is just
something maybe that that has a little
bit more um feedback so you can see
whether it's it's slowing down or
whether it's not slowing down or that
sort of thing and uh and then you are
hoping you know to be able to stop it
and start it pretty easily is that the
main the main problem you see with that
right now yeah see what what are the Tas
but that's the same with the active
scanner of burp you should rule out any
path with geg with images for example or
fonts or css there's not much there so
and if you don't do that it will try to
do uh Pro code injection on the CSS file
yeah which makes no sense
right so yeah you need to limit it
happily to to be effective and this this
blog post on
our I showed that you can also use
intruder if you got a feeling this page
must be formable just go manually I I
almost timate nothing of what I do I
just look carefully about what's going
on what's Happening code so let's say
you identify a cool funky looking
request you send it to to a repeater or
whatever you're playing around with it
do you pretty much instantly send it to
Intruder as well and and launch off a a
uh and then let that run for a little
while look at the responses that are
different and then keep playing with it
that's the that's the flow yeah yeah and
then have at one moment six different
Intruders and you keep refreshing them
and you keep looking at them and then
yeah yeah you're lost on your screen and
then you're think like okay got 20
repeater Taps and now four five six
seven eight Windows of intruder hell oh
man
yeah there definitely needs to be some
organization stuff that that is a little
bit different in that in that area
that's pretty cool though um yeah so I
think server side template injection is
definitely a a a tricky one for me I
definitely I definitely want to grow in
that area I don't have a good flow right
now for using a scanner that would alert
to that sort of thing um mostly the way
that I'm I'm I should be doing it but
I'm not is just putting these you know
curly brackets or angle brackets or
whatever into a part of the like XS
payloads that I'm using and spraying
across the the website is that something
you're doing as well are you mostly
relying on the scanner to detect that no
totally makes sense yeah yeah and and
then you still have the challenge of a
lot of template engines or custom stuff
like file Center is a great example
where you need to know the specific way
they write their template uh Texs uh and
if you if you don't use it in a proper
way or with a variable that's not
existent then you might miss miss the
the the injection so yeah if you're able
to try to figure out some real working
uh uh templates of template Coop
blops that makes sense yeah so so
pivoting a little bit you know you
mentioned before that one of the early
things you did earli with um Amazon was
breaking apart the Android mobile app
and kind of diving into that a little
bit understanding how the API worked to
build this this website or whatever that
was going to make you a millionaire um
and and uh and I think you've you've
done a pretty good job as well just
looking like talking to you at the Live
Hack events and seeing the kind of bugs
you're finding of looking at that
peripheral scope of Android and iOS and
I think a lot of people go down the
Android out uh route but not as many
people go down the iOS route um so can
you talk about your methodology uh uh
with iOS apps and how you're you're
approaching that um to attack these
these bigger organizations yeah so it's
really important I think as a big b
owner
to have a an iPad that is jail broken
and to have an Android that you can use
to easily man in the middle because
um if it's too big of a hassle to man in
the middle all those apps you don't do
it or you lose too much time if it's
super easy to do then you for example in
a Live Hack event you get the new scope
you see okay we've got six apps there we
got some websites okay let's install
those apps right now on my iPad and on
my Android wait for five minutes and
then come back and then just start
trying to man in the middle then and see
what's traffic so my methodology is uh I
got an iPad that I Jail Break with pill
rain pill rain is one of those jailbreak
tools and there's still an iPad
available that you can Jailbreak with
that tool that also updates to some of
the latest IOS versions I think it's the
tablet iph 7 so have a good look on the
pill R website and see which models are
still supported and if the model also
supports one of the latest IOS versions
because that's a problem you need to
have re versions um but the last time I
checked was three four months ago and it
was still working
well um so that's a thing and I got a
spare uh Android phone uh pixel thing
that are rooted but also uh with Android
you can easily do use uh APK metm APK
man in the middle it's on get up so
sometimes I just patch the AP key and
then I install it but I also think here
it's important to to have those devices
separate from your own device because
otherwise you end up with your personal
phones full with strange ads or yeah
keep up your own uh your own security so
have those different devices there also
really helps to open them up and update
just all those apps and see which up
apps can be updated so you got some
check back from the okay there's
something
new this is this is really interesting
uh this APK mitm um tool that you
mentioned here I hadn't actually seen
this before I'd seen something similar
with uh called objection which allows
you to patch apks and then hook in uh
via fra scripts and stuff like that but
this actually seems like it's oriented
specifically more towards um like
getting rid of uh Sur pinning and that
sort of thing it just goes for that so
it's like a one shot let me see if this
works if it does great and then if not
obviously I'm gonna have to go down the
custom route yeah yeah and that's also
sometimes I do so then I go give it a
try with freed or objection and try to
patch it myself there's only one time I
was not able to disable the men in the
middle and that was some heavily up
fiscated app from some government
somewhere on this planet that that had
if I had to patch it I had to patch it
on system call level in iOS and my good
old friend cck GPD was hallucinating too
much to help me out there so I got stuck
in a lot of rabbit holes and then I
figured out again I might need to wait
for other people to figure out how to do
properly most of the time EPK met in the
middle thing works or objection
and then the fun starts then you need to
to use the app and just see what's going
on and is there any hidden
functionality do you need to are you
able to to to get some perks if you are
an artist or if you sell stuff or
whatever you can think get the app
configured in general yeah yeah that
makes sense so that's most of my time I
spend on is understanding how an
application works or where are the edge
cases the the uh I really like what you
said here is get some framework in your
brain to for both excuse me for both
Android and iOS where it reduces
friction to get to the man in the Middle
Point right because a lot of the value
for us as as web hackers is looking at
these apis and what kind of different
apis the mobile app is using as compared
to the the web right um and so if you
have a a system in place okay you know
we download the APK we or on the device
we pull it off with ADB we run you mitm
APK or whatever the name of the thing is
to patch it and then we we send it along
and if it works great if it doesn't fine
you know just having that in place and
not having to think about that whole
thing and the same same flow for iOS um
opens up scope for you when it's easy
and when you when it's not you you can
go a different route or you can choose
to double click in exactly and and and
and and one other important advice is
have two of those tablets because one
day one will break and you have a lot of
stress so I got two iPads I got two
pixels and that removes all the stress
to for me that if something is is
bricked because it's all jailbreaks it's
all that's and you try to update them
and then see if de if pill rain still
works then you don't want to endure this
moments of Truth No you want to be like
okay I got my backup here it's working
if I break this one I still got my
backup there
so yeah that's also an important lesson
I learned it I imagine that helps as
well for like cross user testing like
you don't have to go log out of the app
on this one and log into it on that one
and like all right now I'm just trying
to use two sessions on one iPad you know
it's like oh geez
exactly on on a on a refurbished iPad
that's all refurbished those those
models so it cost nothing you can buy
them on amazon.com and buy them on
Amazon this was not Al by amazoncom
please click my
affiliate give up your dream Jonathan
don't you're never gonna become an
Amazon affiliate oh my gosh
that's no um but you can yeah it cost
nothing and it saves you if it saves you
two hours of headaches or stress then
you got your money back very much worth
it very much worth it um I'm looking
through some of these other things here
on the list and I think next place
you've got two more cool bugs that I
want to go through this this chain of uh
of three bugs in in the healthcare Dutch
Health Care System stuff and I and that
also sort of leads us down the path of
um why the threat model changes with the
different industries that you're in
right uh and I think a lot of times in
the bug Bounty world we are very much
used to um
POC or GTFO sort of things and but I
think this this medium article that you
wrote up on people being able to send
executable files through a a portal that
um was meant for sending patient
information can have tremendous amount
of impact so can you talk to us a little
bit about that assessment and the
vulnerabilities you chain together for
that one yeah
so um I try to bring back everything I
learn from book b in alar just to to to
improve and make make the industry more
maor on the infos uh thing and um one
day I decided to see how a feasible
ransomware attack would look like in
healthare so being a GP myself um I'm
quite vulnerable I got a lot of patient
data um I got a lot of colleagues
running around a lot of clients and so I
started with having a look at one of the
biggest insurance companies in the nland
I'm I'm also so insured by them for my
uh legal problems and at the time they
don't they did not have any responsible
disclosure
policies um but there are like yeah an
organization founded by doctors so I
expected them to be doctor friendly
doctor friendly yeah so there's one
problem there is that they also sell
insurances for cyber uh cyber risk a
ransomware attack where they give a
guaranteed payout for ransomware uh
attack of 100K plus so if you Ure
yourself for a few on bucks then if you
got ransomware then they will pay the
ransomware grip and which is a problem
because in my industry there's no money
so if you run to wormy you get a box of
candies with not tastful candies because
that's all we have in our in our
practice there's not there's no big
money floating around there and you
you've brought those uh Netherlands
candies to the live hacks before it's
like what is it like the black licorice
or something like
that I don't like
that good that you remember that you
were fun of the Str I guess I am the
those are very good those approved yeah
there you go no so so I figured out like
hey they creating a big risk to my
industry um they obiously do it because
people request them to sell those
insurances so get a problem but my
perspective was that's not good but also
like there the first n targets I would
like to hack as a rware group because if
I hack them I know exactly who's insured
for which amount of money and that will
be well my dream come true because then
I could Pino my
attack ah so so you're hacking the
insurance provider to understand okay
this company this company this company
this company all have insurance policies
at 100 Grand so I need to go pop that
one and that one and that one and that
one there you go so that was the moment
when I when I discovered that like oh
wait this might be a thing then I start
poking more into their infrastructure as
I'm a client but I had to be super
careful because I did not have
permission no responsible disclosure
thing there so I was more doing this to
uh do good for society being some sort
of journalist I'm publishing about
security issues so I've got some
protection in the landland but I need to
be careful so um um and I ringed up my
mom my mom is a psychologist and I asked
her like are you also in church with
them and she was like yeah I am so at
that moment I had two accounts on my
left screen I have my mom access on my
right screen myself so I was able to
safely idore my own account from my
mom's and if well [__] hits the fan and
whatever happens with with lawyers and
and judges and I could at least say I
did I did try to only impact myself and
I did to try Etc in the NS you're quite
quite safe if you do
that so that that's when I open up bur
see how it all works and then I figured
out here there's some inbox with all
your PDF documents that request has some
integer of your membership number and I
could replace my member of my mom's
membership number with mine and and that
way I could feel all the PS that were
part of my profile including the
insurance policy term sheet
so o yeah um so I reached out to them
and they they handled this really well
so they patch this backck within hours
or few days and they reached out to me
to discuss how they can improve the
overall security by the end uh of a few
weeks they also published responsible
disclosure um had to to convince
leadership there that it's a good idea
to get
transparency and I think ybert wants put
that on Twitter transparency is trust
and yeah that is one of the most
important parts I think in our society
in our book body programs in um but also
from a customer perspective I want to
know is solving we problem and how you
handled it and and if you learn
something from it's all
good um so I triy to to convince them
also to to let me share the story and
after some debate they agreed on that
and and so that's the the the prop route
to to go it's really good to enforce
change you know via that by bringing to
the public and that sort of thing and
and I think especially in these very
high uh data sensitivity in Industries
it's super important to have at minimum
a responsible disclosure program uh
otherwise otherwise how are how are
people gonna be able to report stuff and
dude it's so common I've actually found
almost an identical bug to the one in
your in your right up here within past
month on a healthare thing in the US
where it's literally just up in the URL
bar you know member ID equals you know
numeric idor and it's like ah this is
really not good yeah yeah and there's no
way we're the only ones seeing this
right like there's there are definitely
other people that look up there and say
if I'm member ID 123 then somebody else
is going to be member ID 124 and that's
not good how did it when when you were
Rec of this was it part of a big b or
resp no it wasn't a part of a bug Bing
program it was something that I used and
and so I went in there and I I was I was
like I opened up this PDF file I
exported it so that I could you know do
something with it and uh you know in the
PDF export of course there's like a you
know they like slash PDF renderer you
know whatever and and just put in the ID
and it generates the output and I I
looked at it and I'm like oh no so I
sent an email and I I um to their
support team because they didn't have
any security contacts and and then I
called the company and said hey I just
sent through an email and they're like
uh we don't really know what to do with
this and I'm like that's fine you know
it's not it's not you just can you pass
it to somebody in it please and uh
within they fixed it within 24 hours
which was amazing yeah um but yeah I
mean they no no email back no response
no nothing just just just and that
that's super important saying we need to
push more for as a society to do all the
people creating like uh the law all the
people in working for governments try to
see what you can do to get every every
piece of infrastructure that holds data
of citizens of your country that they
have some way of that there is some way
to reach out to this infrastructure to
reper security books to but also try to
see if you can enforce or support
transparency because um enforcing stuff
is not good because people find ways
around but if you if you share the
reason why we we need to be transparent
about stuff then you
also create more Awareness on all levels
like hey we might need to bend us
something every once in a while hey we
might might need to check something for
the risks before we deploy it
or and that that that will protect us
from people who want to do harm and in
the healthcare industry rares our
biggest threat at the moment they are
super smart they've got really big
budgets and I I I bet they already fixed
my P Miner book and they were like oh we
have fixed that already because of their
budget but yeah we got we got so much um
stuff Exposed on the internet and if
it's hard to reach out to to to
companies like you had to go through all
the Hoops yeah that that's uh that's
that's work to do and maybe not our work
but um um yeah we need to ask somebody
from the side you know I think I think
one of the things that I haven't seen a
ton of is and like pretty much only I've
seen this from from Jack cable here in
the US and you over over there in the
Netherlands as well is trying to get
involved with the policy creation and
trying to influence that at a big scale
um I think that's really important work
and will make it easier for us to do
these sort of things in the future and
continue to go move forward um with you
know reporting these bugs and getting
them addressed in a way that's and also
get you rewarded for your assessment of
time yeah yeah because people aren't
just going to you know people aren't
going to do it just for free forever you
know and and so there should actually be
some some additional monetary incentive
I think as well yeah I fully agree on
that yeah yeah so so that was the first
hit so we now know in the Netherlands
everyone was insured we should uh uh uh
has for or pinpoint our or Tex on the
second book I found was uh um in an El
as Doctor you need to have some
subscription with um a person that will
handle all your complaint so if you're
not happy with me you can file file some
complaint against me and then this
independent person will try to mediate
and try to figure out how could we learn
from it so it's not like a legal
procedure it's more like get stuff fixed
and get stuff done in a in a proper
quickly way but most doctors use their
private details for that because they
want to be aware of any any problem S as
soon as possible and we received this
stuff just with the ordinary old mail so
um that was my next Target it's a super
smallish organization two people working
there but they have a lot of sensitive
data all the the doctors but also the
psychiatrist working in prisons and
stuff like that they hold all the data
and they had a fil book that if you
signed up for uh a new profile everyone
could sign up you ended your
registration number as a doctor they
call a b number but it's um it's just an
integer code that's public you can find
it everywhere I need to share it also
with you if if you ask me it's the way
you can check if I'm actually a doctor
if you uh enter that in your new signup
profile thing they return an error like
sorry you already have a profile please
log in but if you look in burp you saw
in the response the full Account
Details put it in respon so take home
message here always check yourp for any
responses they might not render it on
the website but it's there in the in the
response so also though they handled it
pretty pretty well and quickly and they
patched it but at that point we had all
the private data of all the doctors also
the doctors were having this really good
insurance policy there's a coverage for
a lot of money if you R
wear um third we need to actually upload
the malware to their systems and the
easiest way is days is just send an
email with an attachment that's my
homeless answer but that's not fancy so
we had to look for something fancy so
there are like seven systems in theet
EHR EHR systems like we use as uh as GPS
sure and I got access to a few of them
and one of my GP buddies parts is also
uh sometimes hacking so I reached out to
Bart and I was like hey dude do you've
got any which systems could you test for
me like I got access to two of them so
get good so we have Cal h of all the
systems so I explained him the thing and
he was like yeah could try that for you
so you want to upload an executable
instead of a picture of the M see oh
yeah makes sense so all P all our
clients can send messages through some
Portal app and can upload and picture so
it's easy for me to I like it's nothing
or yeah at this screen so that moment me
and B start trying to upload executables
and most of them got blocked because
there are some some men in the middle
party that is um
um is doing a lot of those portals but
one of them did not block it so then we
discovered like oh we could just upload
an executable and for me as a doctor it
the executable is displayed in my inbox
of a Windows desktop application all
custom yava I think it's really ancient
Legacy
software
um and I could just click it and it
opened up the executable and we did
approve concept which on setup. action
Nothing Fancy no ransomware but we proof
that we could just send those
executables to specific doctors you can
sign up as a romber group to any doctor
you want to there's no no real uh no no
user what we call privileg required that
will be none or low maybe but I would
say oh my gosh and uh yeah so that was
rce there yeah user interaction required
but still good thing so so I mean
essentially what you did is something
that we talk about you know on the Pod
from time to time here is is building
out that full threat model Vision that
that full attack Vector Vision right you
started with enumerating all of the um
you know doctors and that have these
insurance policies and and then you
figure out a way to actually get that
payload through to the doctor in in a
way that's reasonable and I mean that
that this is beautiful this is really
beautiful because at the end of the day
it makes it so much clearer for um the
the people that are not in this this bug
Bounty world this even people that are
in the security world but not in like
the full let me Pock out this whole
thing World um how how easy it is to put
these pieces together and achieve some
really crazy impact um and I mean this
is exactly how a a a Mal malicious actor
would go about this right so this is do
programmatically for programs I think if
you want to be a great program just say
the scope is our customer data figure a
way out how to hit it and know fing
because that's too easy but think out of
the box and to do that the only way to
do is if we got proper policies in
countries where you are not limited by
other companies suing you because you
found a back in their assistance no we
need to create a way that we can create
those chains because it's not only
amazing stories but it is actually the
way it works in real life with the with
the thread models we have to work with
so I yeah I think this is really good
think this is something that a lot of
programs could really do better on some
some programs will put treasure maps out
there and say like hey we care about
this we care about that but I think
incentivizing full-fledged attack
methodology is really cool so saying
like hey if you can provide some way to
show a vulnerability show distribution
and exploitation of this vulnerability
in Mass then we'll award additional
bounties for that or we'll award bonuses
for that or we'll have a set you know
tier or whatever that you that you reach
to if you're able to provide me with a
reasonable attack Vector uh that chains
things together and makes this attack
that somebody could very easily
Implement exactly and and a mistake I
see programs now making is to put third
party code or stuff like that or
Enterprise sofware out of scope if you
do that you lose big Talent uh because
there are some researchers focused on
that finding your your zero days in your
Enterprise software that holds all the
sensitive data you can think of so start
doing that take responsibility for the
stuff you implement in your company it's
your decision to use this enterprise
software and be aware of any bucks and
if it's a zero day you want to know and
if it's a one day you might also want to
know and um it's the change that that
will be the ones that impress leadership
and and and also protect your customers
or your clients whatever you
EMP so a lot of times this these these
Enterprise softwares I think they were
actually just discussing this last week
on the um on the asset note podcast
surfacing security about how these these
thirdparty vendors are um really
becoming the shadow it of this
generation and and oftentimes the
weakest links are are not this this code
that are part of the main application
but these little vendors that they're
like ah we kind of need this tool but we
don't like fully vet it we just kind of
plop it in on the system and then time
and time again you've SE seen shs in the
whole ACD note crew just destroy those
pieces of software and it's absolutely
detrimental we need so many people like
sheeps in this team sheeps is one of the
most impressive hackers I've met in in
my hacking career super grateful also to
to work together sometimes with him and
what he learns me is that there are so
many weak spots in software that is used
everywhere but you need to inest heavily
on that and you need to to to go deep
really deep and if we don't let that be
part of the buck boundy game or our trap
models because we it's Enterprise or
third party then you lose out on on the
most important bucks you might have and
um yeah yeah I'm I'm super happy that he
is investing on that and and yeah and
doing great
research it's very important I think um
all right I want to be respectful of
your time Dr Bowman but I do have to ask
uh a a couple more questions about this
okay so moving away from the the
technical stuff and bringing it back
around to something that I'm sort of
tangentially um passionate about with
regards to bug Bounty is how we as bug
bounty hunters can take care of our
bodies and take care of our minds uh as
we're doing this very addicting very uh
you know hunched over at our desk for
hours sort of thing right um so as as
the uh official doctor of the bug Bounty
work world tell us what we need to know
about how to maintain our posture how to
keep our brains functioning um you know
in these super long hacking sessions um
what what do you have for us
there yeah it all starts with tetch
theable no
um why do you just pull out a
carrot as a b body Hunter the most
important part is to have a golden plade
with carrots on it way to have a
constant constant way of finding work
now uh old Jokes Aside have have healthy
habits that's the most important thing
and habits you create them by doing
stuff periodically few times a week and
if you do that long enough it becomes a
habit and if it's healthy that it's good
so um for myself I've got the healthy
habit of starting every other day rating
weights it's super boring in B scene I
see quite a few power LS around us I'm
just one
how do you do that I'm not dedicated
enough do
this a healthy habit of going that and
and doing that and doing this for for a
long while I can't think of a situation
where I'm not doing it that's also a
struggle with life occupants then you're
in other environments and you sometimes
don't have the ability to do those
healthy habits or you tend to not do so
try to figure out how to do that um for
me for example two YouTube channels I
use often abroad are M fits and Bully
juice just easy home gym stuff which you
can do without any any
extra you can yeah just do it on your
hotel room I discover that during Co
because all the gyms closed down are
still using it by today um eating yeah
obviously everything you put in your
mouth uh
can be harmful on the other end life is
short so you might enjoy it so yeah
don't be super strict in everything find
the right balance
and people sometimes ask me like hey do
you drink alcohol well most most time I
don't I might drink once a month maybe
once every three four months Max but
that's that's one of the hacks I use to
stay sharp and
focused um I remember from the time I
was a developer I and if I had some
alcohol i f i was had the greatest IDs
and if I look back in the code it was
horrible the next day so that was a good
objective uh observation of that it's
not working well same with weed I Never
Smoke Weed even though I'm from am but
something F same with with weed I've
never smoked weed in my life um for some
people it works and there's quite a high
rate of add or ADHD bount people
having so that's often the reason people
use we to get some Focus or some some
mind states that works for them but also
there are other ways that are more
healthy to do so yeah I'm not telling
you you're doing wrong but there's
there's different ways to cope with the
problem what I I'm not sure if this is
your Arena because I know that like
posture health and that sort of thing is
something that's that's kind of
different from you know general medicine
stuff uh it's more in the physical
therapist realm but um I I recently uh
had an injury in my shoulder and um as I
went to go talk to a doctor about it you
know he was saying that um from working
at a desk you know the shoulders are
sort of slunch slunch forward like this
a little bit and um because of that the
pectoral muscle is is
shortened and it's pull and it's pulling
the shoulder down right and so one of
the things that he he had me do it's
been amazing for my posture and really
helped with my ability to like reach and
and swing when I hit a volleyball is um
he's had me take like this ball like a
lacrosse ball or like a tennis ball and
like lean my chest up against a wall and
push this ball into my chest muscle to
loosen up this muscle right here and
that pushes that allows for this muscle
to be extended a little bit more and
allows for my back muscles to pull those
shoulders back into place oh wow that's
amazing and I was like I was like man
this is like this is the kind of stuff I
need to know about you know like these
hacks to keep keep the posture you know
up straight when you're hunched over the
computer normally because I think a lot
of us get so in the zone with bug Bounty
where we're like not even thinking about
you know we're sitting like sideways and
like you know exactly all the levels I
owe stuff um yeah infesting yourself and
get a phys therapist also maybe once you
got some problems with posture I I try
to sit in different positions all the
time yeah I've heard that that's big is
changing the position that you're in not
just not any given position but just
changing on a pretty regular basis yeah
so that works for me but it might not
work for other people but it works quite
well for me and uh in a lot of my jobs
I've got a sitting uh I got to sit down
and in my work as a doctor I sit on some
strange old chair that looks like if you
sit on a horse I'm not sure what a word
for that is but the um like a saddle
yeah like a sadle and that also makes
you like sit in all different ways and
that works for me um and with with all
the complaints you have and the thing is
with muscles is
the it starts with if you have a problem
there you can go to phys therapy get
some massage and then the problem is
gone for a few hours and then comes back
so you need to learn how to stretch the
muscle you need to learn after that how
to train the muscle and if you improved
Foundation of all your mou you are less
prone to to catch another pain or
problem so that's why you also should
start doing sports even though you don't
have any problems at the moment just to
stay in the safe Zone and then we're
getting older and older and older and
when getting older stuff got worn out
and that's part of
life the only thing you can do is is
start training and and keep training
it's it's important to be consistent
about it too like said because for a
really long time I was doing I was in
the gym you know 5 days a week and
lifting and that sort of thing and then
you know I've recently had uh a a a
child in the family and uh and when you
have that things get a little bit
difficult you don't get as much
flexibility in life and and so I stopped
going to the gym um and stopped lifting
as regularly and uh you know it wasn't
six months after that happened that I I
threw out this Arm playing volleyball
and dislocated my shoulder and had this
whole this whole problem start that i'
I've been clawing my way back now for
for one month you know or longer than a
month actually just trying to get this
shoulder back in a position where I can
use it so um it's it's you know is is a
little bit of a tough lesson for me that
even if you are um you know lifting on a
pretty regular basis if you just stop
for just six months that's enough for
the degradation to to occur and for some
some injury to to happen yeah yeah so so
if your habits have just like the iPads
have two of the those iPads you can
Jailbreak also have this this this thing
uh a backup a backup plan like the the
YouTube videos and then you make the
agreement with yourself okay I can't go
to gym I'll do this 30 minute workout
just home and so keep moving and yeah
it's a great idea that's a great idea Dr
Bowman all right thank you so much for
joining us man I I I appreciate it so
many different areas of wisdom across
collaboration across hacking across
um really a pleasure thanks for coming
on the Pod man thank you for thei and uh
yeah if anyone finds good Ducks hope to
hear that on your podcast if you find
Buck on file sender let them know they
need more eyes and uh yeah happy
to to to meet the people on the on the
Discord I think I'm not sure if I joined
already but I'll I'll have a look around
so feel free to thank you so much that's
the Pod peace
[Music]